

· weichen6@stanford.edu · (650) 283-5669 · https://www.linkedin.com/in/wei-chen-stanford/ · Stanford, CA, US, 94305

# **CAREER SUMMARY**

Machine learning engineer with roughly 1.5-year working experience and 3-year research training on **deep learning**, **deep reinforcement learning** and **development of large numerical simulation software**. My expertise lies in:

- Design, train, tune and deploy state-of-art machine learning model to solve real-world and research-oriented problems.
- C++ and Python based large software development, with **optimization** in speed and memory.

### **EDUCATION**

Stanford University, Stanford, US

Sep. 2019 - Jun. 2023

PhD in Artificial Intelligence and Numerical Linear Algebra in Engineering, CEE Department. GPA: 4.0/4.0

Tongji University, Shanghai, China

Sep. 2015 - Jul. 2019

Bachelor in Engineering, awarded Outstanding Graduate of China Civil Engineering Society, First prize of Chinese College Students Mathematics Competition. GPA: 93.67/100, 1st/439

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AI Team Lead, Collov. inc, Redwood city, CA

Sep. 2020 - present

Lead the software development team (8 members) in US and China to create web-based AI service to aid the home interior design, and build the shopping recommendation system.

- Furniture recommendation system, and customer preference analysis based on CNN.
  - Utilized computer vision algorithms/frameworks including EfficientNet, CLIP, MASKRCNN, STYLEGAN to do commodity and design generation/recommendations based on submitted design projects, contributing over 3M revenue per year and 5000+ customers.
  - Designed and deployed CNN models in furniture area with classification accuracy over 98.5% based on dataset with 2M goods. Worked on the AI-aid interior design system based on similarity search and style analysis to reduce the design period by 80%.
- Prediction and decision making system using Graph Neural Network (GNN)
  - O Constructed the **enterprise heterogeneous large knowledge graph** including goods, users and interior design case as nodes utilizing **1M** goods, **5K** customers and **10K** design cases.
  - O Designed domain-specific Collov-Net to do goods recommendation (0.2 recall for top 50, and 0.6 precision), furniture similarity analysis (with 99.7% precision, over CNN model), and decision making (increase the revenue of after-design shopping by 13%, reduce the design time by 95%).
  - Use GraphRNN and deep reinforcement learning to do set prediction, generating the design automatically.
- 3D-AR-AI virtual showroom for furniture
  - Using graph neural network recommendation system to select the background and exhibits for different users.
  - o Create ios software to leverage the 3D-AR showroom with web-based AI service.

Software Developer (Research Assistant), Stanford Civil and Environmental Department, CA

Sep. 2019 - present

- Large distributed numerical simulation platform (**Geocentric**) for parallel solver of multivariate differential equations.
  - o Implemented 3D numerical solver for coupled partial differential equations for solid deformation, multiphase fluid flow and chemical reaction. Optimized the memory (-14%) and runtime (-20%) in unit test using iterative numerical solver.
  - Incorporated state-of-art laws of physics, and designed generic preconditioner matrix to converge high nonlinear partial differential system.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CNN-aided Solver of Partial Differential Equation (PDE), Stanford | Advisor: Prof. Ronaldo Borja

Jun. 2020 - present

- Designed an architecture (**ResNetUNet**) to combine ResNet and UNet to facilitate the heterogeneous PDE solver, with **0.52%** relative error for solution in static case.
- Use ResNetUNet as the pretrained model and design both **transformer** and **LSTM** to conduct time series video prediction with **0.61%** relative error.

Physics Informed Neural Network (PINN) aided Solver of PDE, Stanford | Advisor: Prof. Ronaldo Borja Jan. 2022 - present

- Designed and trained neural network to represent physics laws in linear elasticity, Mohr–Coulomb and Cam-Clay plasticity.
- Integrate the PINN and finite element method to enable the computation of highly nonlinear PDE.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Programming: Python (proficient), C/C++ (proficient), Advanced data structure and algorithm.
- Operation System & Database: Linux/Unix, Windows, MongoDB, Flask.
- Machine Learning & Cloud Services: TensorFlow, Pytorch, Pytorch Geometry, Amazon AWS, Google Cloud, Docker, VSCode.
- Data Analytics: Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Seaborn, Re, Weights and bias.